<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Commune Concilium tentum in Camera Guild-hall, ciuitatis London, septimo die Aprilis, anno regni Domini nostri, Iacobi regis Angliæ ... an Act for Reformation of the Negligences of Constables, and of the Abuses and Misdemeanors of Apprentices, Carmen,and Others, of and for the Better Apprehension of the Offenders.</title>
            <title>Act for Reformation of the Negligences of Constables, and of the Abuses and Misdeameanors of Apprentises, Carmen, and Others, of and for the Better Apprehension of the Offenders.</title>
            <author>City of London (England).</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1621</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06239</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16728.3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S1338</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">22134502</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 22134502</idno>
            <idno type="VID">25127</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06239)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 25127)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1731:5)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Commune Concilium tentum in Camera Guild-hall, ciuitatis London, septimo die Aprilis, anno regni Domini nostri, Iacobi regis Angliæ ... an Act for Reformation of the Negligences of Constables, and of the Abuses and Misdemeanors of Apprentices, Carmen,and Others, of and for the Better Apprehension of the Offenders.</title>
                  <title>Act for Reformation of the Negligences of Constables, and of the Abuses and Misdeameanors of Apprentises, Carmen, and Others, of and for the Better Apprehension of the Offenders.</title>
                  <author>City of London (England).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] leaves.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By VVilliam Iaggard, printer to the honourable citie of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1621]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Constables --  Law and legislation --  England --  London.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:25127:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure> Commune Concilium tentum in Camera Guild-Hall, Ciuitatis London, ſeptimo die Aprilis, Anno Regni Domini noſtri, Iacobi Regis Angliae, Franciae, &amp; Hiberniae, fidei defenſor. &amp;c. xix. et Scotiae quinquageſimo quarto: Coram Franciſco Iones milite, Maiore Ciuitatis London, Heanagio Finch Armigero, Recordatore eiuſdem Ciuit. Thoma Bennet milite, Thoma Low milite, Io<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hanne Leman milite, Edwardo Barkham, Alexandro Preſcot, Petro Proby, Willielmo Gore, Alano Cotton, Cutberto Hacket, Willielmo Holli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day, Richardo Herne, Hugone Hamerſly, &amp; Richardo Deane, Aldermannis; ac Edwardo Allen, &amp; Roberto Ducy eiuſdem Ciuitatis Vicecomitibus: Nec non maiori parte Communiariorum dictae Ciuitat. exiſtent. aſſemblat. &amp;c.</head>
            <head type="sub">An Act for Reformation of the negligences of Conſtables, and of the Abuſes and miſdemeanors of Apprentiſes, Carmen, and others, of and for the better apprehenſion of the Offenders.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas many times heretofore Complaints haue beene made by diuers the Nobles and great Perſons of the Realme, and others, that haue oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion to paſſe the ſtreets, of many rude behauiours vſed towards them by Apprentiſes, Carmen, and others: And now lately, an audacious and inſolent affront hath bene offered to the perſon of the Lord Ambaſſador to the King of <hi>Spaine,</hi> &amp; ſome of his ſeruants and followers to the great diſhonor &amp; ſcandall of the publike Gouernment of the City, &amp; at which the Kings moſt excellent Maieſty (as he hath iuſt cauſe) is highly offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded: which diſorders are conceiued to ariſe and grow, partly through the neglect of Conſtables, who are not ready to be found when complaint is made: &amp; partly through the default of the Inhabitants, who are not ready to ayde and aſſiſt the Conſtables and Officers in the apprehenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Offenders: much leſſe to apprehend the Offenders themſelues, and bring them to ſome Officer or miniſter of Iuſtice; and partly for want of good inſtruction and admonition giuen by Maſters of Families, to their Children, Seruants, and Apprentiſes.</p>
            <p>For remedy whereof, and for preuention of like abuſes hereafter, Be it enacted by the right Honourable the Lord Mayor of this City, the right Worſhipfull the Aldermen his Brethren, and the Commons in this Common Councell aſſembled, and by Authority of the ſame, That euery Conſtable within the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and the Liberties therof, ſhal haue his Conſtable-ſtaffe (during all the time that he ſhalbe Conſtable) ſtand at his doore, openly to be ſeene, to the end that euery man that hath occaſion to vſe the aide or aſſiſtance of a Conſtable, may know where to find him. And alſo that euery Conſtable, ſhall either by himſelfe (or if hee haue iuſt occaſion to be abſent) by ſome fit and ſufficient perſon deputed by him be ready to performe the duty of his place, in apprehending of Fellons, Vagrants, and other Offenders, and conueighing them to priſons fit for them: And in repreſſing of Riots, reſcues of Priſoners, or perſons led to puniſhment, and other diſorders: and in the executing all other things pertaining to the Office of a Conſtable, vpon paine to forfeite twenty ſhillings for euery default, the ſame to be imployed to the vſe of the poore of the Pariſh, where the Offence is committed.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:25127:2"/>
            <p>And be it further enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any iuſt Complaint be heereafter made of any violence or miſdemeanor that ſhall be done or offered to any Ambaſſador, Noble perſon, Ladies, Gentlewo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, or others, paſſing through the ſtreets. And that any Houſholder or Inhabitant ſhall bee required either by the Conſtable, his deputy, or the party greeued, to apprehend ſuch Offender or Offenders, and detaine them vntill they may be brought before a Iuſtice of the peace, That then euery perſon and perſons ſo required, ſhall accordingly ayde and aſſiſt vpon paine of ſuch fine as to the Court of Lord Maior and Aldermen, vpon exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of the nature of the offence ſhall ſeeme reaſonable.</p>
            <p>And for the better preuention of ſuch diſorders and abuſes heereafter, &amp; that all Offenders in this kind here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after may be without excuſe, It is heereby further enacted and enioyned, that all the Aldermen within their ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ueral Wards reſpectiuely, or their deputies, ſhall forthwith giue perſonall warning and admonition to euerie Houſholder and Maſter of a Family, within the City and Liberties thereof, that they themſelues take know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, and do ſtrictly charge and admoniſh all and euery their Children, Seruants, and Apprentiſes, that both they, their Children, Seruants, and Apprentiſes, do from henceforth carrie and demeane themſelues well and orderly towards all Ambaſſadors, Noble perſons, Ladies, Gentlewomen, and others whatſoeuer, that ſhall haue occaſion to paſſe through the ſtreets, and do neither throw, nor ſhoote any thing at them, nor miſ-behaue themſelues towards them, either in geſture, words, or action: nor ſhall vſe vpon the <hi>Exchange,</hi> nor in any ſtreet or lane of the City, any vnciuill ſport, as Trap, Squibs, Foote-ball, or the like, vpon paine of ſeuere puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to be inflicted vpon them, according to the quality of the offence.</p>
            <p>And to repreſſe the rude and vnmannerly behauiour of Carmen, Carters, Draymen and others, vſing or working any Carre, Cart or Dray whatſoeuer, It is alſo enacted and declared by the Authority aforeſaid, that not onely all and euery the Acts of Common Councell and Orders of this City heretofore made for the Gouernment of them, be put in due execution, but alſo that the Maſter and Wardens of the Woodmongers of this City, doe admoniſh them particularly, not to commit any ſuch diſorders hereafter that may giue iuſt cauſe of offence. And that the ſaid Maſter and Wardens doe performe in all poynts, the Act of Common Councell made in that behalfe in the time of the Mayoralty of Sir <hi>Iohn Leman</hi> knight, late Lord Mayor of this City, concerning Cars and Carmen. Aſſuring them that a ſtrict accompt ſhalbe taken thereof, and ſeuere puniſhments inflicted vpon any of them that ſhal offend in that behalfe, according to the quality of their offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces. And all Houſholders &amp; Inhabitants are hereby likewiſe enioyned to be ayding and aſſiſting to the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble or other Officer that ſhall apprehend ſuch Offenders, and themſelues likewiſe in default of an Officer to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend and deteine ſuch an Offender, till he may be brought before ſome Iuſtice of the Peace, vpon peine of ſuch Fine as to the Court of Lord Mayor and Aldermen, vpon examination of the offence ſhall ſeeme reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble.</p>
            <closer>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> God ſaue the King. <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at London, by William Iaggard, Printer to the Honourable Citie of London.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
